<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: fitness | Zachary Zadell]]></title>
  <link href="http://zadell.com/categories/fitness/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zadell.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-01T21:56:23-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zadell.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zachary Zadell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mount Rainier]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2011/mount-rainier/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-24T16:32:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2011/mount-rainier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/6070827576/"><img class="center" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6062/6070827576_18a973e840_b.jpg"></a></p>

<h2>You In?</h2>

<p>About 10 days ago I got an email from one of the friends I climbed Hood with
asking if I wanted to climb Rainier. It contained a short description of the
hike and ended with "It will be a miserable and wonderful experience. You in?"</p>

<p>He honestly didn't even need to ask. Even after it was all over and I could
barely stand, when simple things like opening a beer would cause me to cramp
up, did I feel the same way as I did then - of course I was in.</p>

<p>I think I have reached a stage in my life where simply because something is
difficult is not reason enough not to do it. When I look back at the past year
one of the things I think of most fondly is my Summit of Hood back in June.
Whenever I am about Portland and I catch a glimpse of Hood I can't help but
feel a tremendous sense of accomplishment knowing that I conquered such a
gigantic mountain.</p>

<p>What better gift to myself than to be able to claim that I conquered another
mountain?</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/6070864990/"><img class="center" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6201/6070864990_fe656c11ce_b.jpg"></a></p>

<h2>What's Involved</h2>

<p>The Rainier summit is at 14,411 ft compared to Hood's 11,249 ft. In several of
my shots there is a mountain called Little Tahoma that seems tiny when on the
mountain. It is actually only 100 ft smaller than Mount Hood.</p>

<p>This climb up Rainier is much longer than Hood was. The very last part of
Hood, where you need an ice axe to self bellet yourself is probably more
technically challenging than anything I encountered on Rainier, but beyond
that Rainier is in a different league of difficulty because of the endurance
you will need.</p>

<p>Rumor has it that someone went from the parking lot to the top of the mountain
and back in 5 hours. We would be traveling with a 90 liter pack filled with
gear, food and clothing, which would mean we would be traveling much slower
than he did.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/6070277665/"><img class="center" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6189/6070277665_f10288fa08_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Weight was always on my mind. None of my gear is particularly light. My pack
is about 15 years old and no where near being ideal for climbing mountains
with. I elected to leave my relatively heavy Nikon D90 + Sigma 10-20 combo that I
adored on Hood home in exchange for a much lighter (if damaged) Canon G9. My
G9 has been through quite a bit so it is filled with dust and if I ever tried
to change its focal length it would lock up and give a lens error. I really
wish I could have spared the weight but realize that many of the shots that I
did get would not have happened if I had to fumble through my pack constantly
to retrive my camera.</p>

<p>The hike involves leaving early in the morning from the
Paradise parking lot with all your gear. From there you will travel roughly 4
hours to Camp Muir. The trip up was relatively easy. I was fresh and my pack
felt light. Despite the length of the hike most of the people doing it were
approaching it as a day hike - so up to Camp Muir and back.</p>

<p>Like many others though we were in it to go all the way. We arrived at Muir
shortly after noon and then spent the next 12 hours sleeping, filtering water
and cooking. We were really concerned about having to carry a tent so we
sprinted to Muir to make sure that we had a spot in the first come first serve
hut that is available to climbers for free.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/6070260203/"><img class="center" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6067/6070260203_c0f96e8dee_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p>We were able to get good spots and shortly after the place filled up with people who would be
waking up the same time as we did to tackle the mountain. It seems everyone
had the same plan and woke up around midnight to eat some breakfast, gear up
and head out for what would be much more difficult climb than the first half of
the mountain.</p>

<p>By the end of the climb I was so exhausted that I had to break frequently to
make the short walk to the actual summit. Without realizing it I was nearly on
the verge of tears as we celebrated the climb. Was it the hardest thing I had
ever done? Maybe. Most exhausting? Definitely.</p>

<p>The hardest part of the experience was realizing you had to climb
all the way back down again though. Shale and sliding snow made for a really
uncomfortable trip down.</p>

<h2>How long does it take?</h2>

<p>Total trip broke down to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Hike to Camp Muir: 4 hours</li>
<li>Resting at Camp Muir then waking up at midnight: 12 hours</li>
<li>Hiking from Muir to Summit: 8 hours</li>
<li>From Summit back down to Muir: 5 hours</li>
<li>From Muir to the parking lot: 3 hours.</li>
</ul>


<p>So in total about 32 hours.</p>

<p>My favorite moments were waking up in the middle of night, gazing up at a
perfectly clear star-filled sky, and seeing St Helens silhouetted by the glow
of Portland.</p>

<p>I also enjoyed catching the first glow of the morning sky on the mountain and
watching it change the color of the landscape.</p>

<p>Finally I enjoyed butt sliding the rest of the way down the mountain and
arriving at a wild flower filled mountain fed stream that meant we would have
water to drink that didn't involve melting snow.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading and enjoy the rest of the pictures. The rest of my shots
and video from the trip can be found at on my <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/sets/72157627370662365/with/6070324037/">flickr set</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/6070862664/"><img class="center" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6073/6070862664_17766d24b9_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/6070803122/"><img class="center" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6193/6070803122_7ea463fd57_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/6070868716/"><img class="center" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6192/6070868716_f383f0f060_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/6070849602/"><img class="center" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6189/6070849602_a5c37f15a0_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p><em>All pictures taken with a Canon G9</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summiting Mount Hood]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2011/summiting-mount-hood/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-07T17:44:46-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2011/summiting-mount-hood</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5801412964/"><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5316/5801412964_e30f23d3ce_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Whenever I cross the Morrison bridge on a clear day in Portland one particular
object seems to stand out on the horizon - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Hood">Mount Hood</a>.
Hood is the highest mountain in Oregon at 11,249 ft yet around 10,000 people a year climb it. Now every
time that I see it I can say I am one of them.</p>

<p>This past Thursday a good friend of mine invited me to climb it and I quickly
agreed to it. The exact conversation went like this:</p>

<p><strong>Craig</strong>: want to climb a mountain?</p>

<p><strong>me</strong>: yes</p>

<p><strong>Craig</strong>: Hood?</p>

<p><strong>me</strong>: yep</p>

<p><strong>Craig</strong>: Have time Friday night/Saturday morning?</p>

<p><strong>me</strong>: yep</p>

<p>The next day I made my way to the local REI to rent and purchase some gear (an
Ice Axe, Helmet and Head Lamp) and that night found myself in the Timberline
parking lot freezing my ass off. Joining us on the hike were two others - Jon
and Tom. Everyone but myself had climbed Hood at least once before, with Tom
having climbed it three times previously.</p>

<p>The first words Tom spoke after parking the car and feeling the wind and
coldness - "OK let's go back now." Maybe it was the excitement or maybe it was
because of the month I had spent working in Copenhagen during the winter, but
the cold wasn't affecting me at all. I actually stripped down to my underwear
and changed in the middle of the parking lot while everyone else huddled in
the car.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5800822641/"><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2087/5800822641_29c6542bff_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p>We started the climb at 1:40am. Climbers try to Summit before the sun fully
rises as the final part of the hike can get dangerous when the snow begins to
melt and freeze. So by doing it early you attempt to avoid that danger.</p>

<p>The day before the hike I mentally prepared myself for it. A few years ago I
climbed <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/sets/72157606145105082/">South Sisters</a>
so I had some experience with climbing. Namely that no matter what shape that I was
in physically there would come a time where I would be looking at my feet
focusing on each individual step and would have to will myself to continue on.
This happened quite often during the hike.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5800830697/"><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3267/5800830697_87ba4236a4_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5801391942/"><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3461/5801391942_4fddd0eee0_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Despite the strong winds we managed to completely avoid losing any gear. At
least 3 times we had a piece of equipment fly off down the mountain only to be
chased down and retrieved by Craig.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5801399002/"><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5067/5801399002_92de94a5fd_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5801404006/"><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2342/5801404006_9d116ab4d3_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p>One of my favorite parts of the hike was when the sun was still rising on the
other side of the mountain. This would cause the snow to melt and blow over
the peak. The sun would catch on the snow and light it up.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5801407450/"><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3556/5801407450_d0e713bf9b_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5800856449/"><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2653/5800856449_58e15b51d4_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p>We kept a pretty slow pace. The softness of the snow ment that if your footing
wasn't sure then you would be sliding back down. Repeating that over thousands
of steps is very exhausting. So we weren't surprised to see lots of teams pass
us on the way up and then back down again.</p>

<p>The hardest part of the hike was dealing with the strong and cold winds. Often
I would have to stop and kneel during the hike until the wind died down.</p>

<p>When we got past Crater Rock and on to the the Hogsback we learned that many teams were turning back and not
completing the summit due to the weather conditions. By the time we were there
though the weather had cleared up enough that it wasn't completely insane to
make the final traversal from the Pearly Gates to the Summit.</p>

<p>The climb up to the Pearly Gates was one of the more difficult parts of the
hike. To accomplish this climb we needed to equip our grampons, helmets and
use our ice axes. Equipping my grampons was particularly challenging due to
the extreme snow flurries that would blow past us on the Hogsback. More than
once I had to pause and heat my hands back from numbness.</p>

<p>Using the ice axe and grampons was a whole new challenge for myself. It was a
slow process of planting the axe handle into the ice and using it belay
yourself while you kick your feet into solid footing. The entire time there is
the risk that you will slip and slide down uncontrollably into a crevice at
the bottom.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5801414860/"><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5319/5801414860_9274fe7933_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p>8 Hours later though and we were at the top.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5801421406/"><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2242/5801421406_1a6464af25_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5800869465/"><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5186/5800869465_32a2f800c0_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5800875441/"><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3198/5800875441_4a5b758fbf_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5800862369/"><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3578/5800862369_07d54cf9d7_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p>The trip back down was actually the hardest part of the hike. Coming up we
couldn't actually see how far we had to go or how high we had to climb because
of the darkness. Going down was just the opposite and the parking lot never
seemed to ever get closer while my body began to hurt more and more.</p>

<p>After all of it though I can now look on Hood and say to myself that I had
conquered it. Which is a pretty good feeling. It was a hard hike but I
honestly enjoyed every bit of it.</p>

<p><em>All pictures were taken using my Nikon D90 and Sigma 10-20 lens.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back in Copenhagen]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2011/back-in-copenhagen/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-11T23:32:17-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2011/back-in-copenhagen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5518490687/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5178/5518490687_0bec7878d0_b.jpg" alt="Copenhagen Train Station Panorama" /></a></p>

<p>I am spending a month working in Copenhagen.</p>

<p>The weather here isn't exactly pleasant. The strange combination of cold,
wind, rain and snow means I am not spending much time outdoors. On my walks to
and from work I am bundled up and am amazed to see people going for jogs or
riding their bikes without their face or heads covered while it is raining and
freezing.</p>

<p>My time here has actually been healthier than usual despite being in a foreign
country. I chalk this up to two factors: 1) My apartment/hotel has a clean
pool and decent weight room 2) the food here is pretty lackluster. Combine
those traits with the craptastic weather and I have yet to really leave my
apartment except to go to work.</p>

<p>I feel zero desire to eat out because everything is bland and over priced and
I am working out and swimming every day. Food wise I have been following a
slow-carb diet which does away with carbs like sugars, pastas and breads. So
it is mostly vegetables and proteins. My most common meal has been eggs, beans
and some frozen vegetables. Yummy.</p>

<p>At the office we get catered lunches. Everyone always complains about the
quality but it is a perk that I definitely appreciate and don't get to take
advantage of because I work remotely. There is just enough variety that I
don't have to deviate from my diet.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5514732854/"><img class="right" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5140/5514732854_4ce4d6fee6_d.jpg"></a></p>

<p>I plan to spend my first weekend here decompressing from a busy but productive
week of work by mostly reading on my kindle. The weather is going to be decent
- at least rain and snow isn't on the forecast. I hope to be able to get out
and grab some more pictures or chill in a cafe some place.</p>

<p>The upcoming weekends should be more interesting though. So far I have booked
weekend trips to London and Paris. It will be my first time traveling to
either place. Both flights have me leaving Friday after work and returning
Sunday night. Once you are in Europe it is pretty remarkable where you can
travel to for 100-200 bucks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Snow Boarding Mount Hood]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2011/snow-boarding/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-02T20:16:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2011/snow-boarding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5314864412/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5245/5314864412_b8f2048fd4_b.jpg" alt="View at Mount Hood" /></a></p>

<p>I have been living in Portland for just about a year now. One of the big draws
of Portland was how close it was to Mount Hood and we envisioned heading to
this place every weekend. In reality we didn't even go once the entire year. I
wanted to start the year off differently though and celebrate it with a snow
boarding trip. Despite the cost and the fear of it being extremely crowded
given the fresh snow and weekend it turned out to be fantastic.</p>

<p>All the pictures taken for this post were made with my iphone. While I would
have loved to have used my DSLR there, some times the best camera is the one
you have with you. I use an app called AutoStitch which creates a panorama
from a bunch of pictures. Most of the panoramas that I take use anywhere from
three to nine pictures.</p>

<p>My girlfriend and I learned how to board together a few years ago. We go very
sporadicly, so every time it feels like we have to learn the basics over
again. By the time we are finish we feel like we know what we are doing but
then the process repeats itself.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5314866632/"><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5201/5314866632_b7853a7835_b.jpg" title="Snow Boarding Pro" ></a></p>

<p>We don't own a 4wd vehicle so we used a bus service to get to Mount Hood. This
involves parking our car some place, then sleeping on the bus for 2 hours
while the driver deals with parking and the snow. Once there we rented the
boards and boots.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5314268817/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5001/5314268817_1c2fcae95b_b.jpg" alt="Tough Spot" /></a></p>

<p>On my very first run my worst fear happened: I had no idea how to interpret
the route signs and some how stumbled upon a run that was way above my level.
I quickly lost momentum and found myself surrounded by trees in fresh, deep
snow. When I tried to move myself I would sink into the snow. The weather was
absolutely perfect though and I didn't really care. At one point I found
myself at the top of a very steep hill that looked very dangerous. I butt slid
around and eventually realized that I was surrounded by similar tracks.
Apparently I wasn't the only person to recently be in the same situation.
Eventually I pushed and hiked my way through the snow until I got to a clear
hill and was on my way again.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5318278146/"><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5049/5318278146_155bae42da_b.jpg" title="Cascade Express" ></a></p>

<p>After spending some time around the newbie coarse I eventually became more
comfortable riding the snow board and decided to make my way up the mountain.
After taking the above picture I was entranced by the beauty of the mountain,
only to realize shortly afterwards that I was no longer holding my glove. I
glanced over my shoulder just as it hit the snow. I spent the rest of the trip
trying to memorize a route to my glove and planning how the heck I would get
down there without my glove. I opted to use my inner fleece as a glove (which
worked horribly) and had to make frequent stops to warm my hand. Shortly
before reaching it though another boarder had picked it up and deposited it at
the entrance. Thanks man!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5314269251/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5170/5314269251_fe2bf10572_b.jpg" alt="View from Cascade Express at Mount Hood" /></a></p>

<p>Despite worrying about my glove I couldn't help but snap the above panorama at
Cascade Express.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5314865694/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5245/5314865694_5eb217db04_b.jpg" alt="Snow Boarding Pro 2" /></a></p>

<p>Throughout the day I couldn't help but appreciate just how lucky I was to be
where I was - perfect weather and snow, tearing down a beautiful mountain. It
was an amazing way to celebrate the end of an awesome year and the beginning
of a new one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning to Run Again with Vibram Five Fingers]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2010/learning-to-run-again-with-vibram-five-fingers/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-27T02:56:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2010/learning-to-run-again-with-vibram-five-fingers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4079/4997164722_061f7d95a8_b.jpg" title="Vibram Fivefingers KSO Trek" ></p>

<p>When I was in high-school I used to run on the cross-country team. It was a
way for me to train in the off seasons between baseball and wrestling.
Eventually I actually became decent recording my fastest 5k time at around 19
minutes, which translates to about a 6 minute mile pace.</p>

<p>It was never easy and I never enjoyed it.</p>

<p>I remember starting every race without imagining what it would be like to
finish it. I simply put one foot in front of the other and kept pace with a
buddy until I could see the finish line - then I would sprint across it like a
mad man and puke my guts out.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3291/3015371980_6874e1ab49.jpg" title="Cross Country with Michael" ></p>

<p>I kept it up a little bit in college but over the years simply gave up on it. I think
around 5 years ago I was still able to run at an 8 minute mile pace.
Eventually though my knee began to hurt when I ran. Without a doubt my pains
are a result of years of playing tennis aggressively. There was a point when I
was playing almost daily that I couldn't imagine there being a ball that I
wouldn't try to track down and return. One day though something clicked and
since then there wasn't a hitting session or run that wouldn't end with my
knee swelling up and me being barely able to walk for a day.</p>

<p>I asked a doctor what could be done. He looked at my knee and determined that
there wasn't anything toren but there was a build up of cartilage that would
require surgery to remove. His advice: give up tennis - it simply wasn't worth
going through surgery when my knee was only aggravated when I played tennis.</p>

<p>As you could imagine this didn't sit well with me - after all tennis is
something that I love. It did force me to evaluate what exactly it was about
tennis that caused my knee to hurt. My conclusion was that it was caused by
the constant pounding, starting and stopping that occurs during tennis - all
of which is felt by my knee. Tennis shoes have an immense amount of padding on
the heel which only encourages you to drive your foot harder into the ground.</p>

<p>The more my knee hurt that more I hated myself for not running over the years.
I missed the days when I used to be able to fly across a field faster than the
wind. Now the very thought of it would cause my knee to ache.</p>

<p>My running stride in the past has always been very long. Where each stride I
would drive my heel into the ground and bound off of it like a deer. I used to
want to replicate the covers of running magazines that I saw when I was a kid.
Running shoes by their very nature encourage this type of stride despite how
un-natural it is. Try it for yourself - take off your shoes and go run across
a field. You will find that you will naturally land on the balls of your feet.</p>

<p>The human foot is the result of hundreds of thousands of years of evolution
and yet a couple of decades of marketing by shoe manufacturers have convinced
people that it is flawed and that they should be <em>corrected</em>. It was this line
of reasoning and the book Born to Run that lead me to buying the craziest
looking shoes that I had ever seen - Vibram Five Fingers.</p>

<p>I had put off buying a pair for well over a year. First because they aren't
exactly good looking, and second because I had a perfectly good pair of
running shoes. The selection of these expensive running shoes were the result
of going to a running store and having my stride recorded and analyzed so that
I would have the perfect running shoe for my feet. Compared to any other shoe
that I had ever had - running in these felt great. The only problem though is
that whenever I ran fast, I would go into my comfortable stride that involved
driving my heels into the ground which would lead to my knee hurting and me
regretting my decision to run.</p>

<p>The basic point of Vibram Five Finger shoes is to replicate what it is like to
be barefooted while still having the excellent traction and durability of a
Vibram sole. I went with the KSO (keep stuff out) trek model. Vibram makes a
model that is geared specifically towards road running, but I wanted something
that I could take on trails while still looking some what inconspicuous. The
average VFF has wild colors that I think most VFF enthusiasts appreciate
because they love the attention that they bring. I just wanted to be able to
run pain free.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4153/5029224752_a4d697649d.jpg"></p>

<p>It has been about 10 days since I got my pair of VFF. During that time I have
logged 21 miles and ran more consistently than I have ever before - or been
able to in the past. It feels awesome to wake up and actually want to be able
to run again instead of dreading the pain that would follow.</p>

<p>My stride has changed drastically. I have been trying for the past year to run
on the balls of my feet, but VFF make it so much easier. Instead of long
strides I now take short, quick steps that land below my center of gravity
rather than in front of it.</p>

<p>The result of this new way of running is that my stride is way more economical
than it used to be and my dropping 5k time is proof of it. I now feel like I
can run longer and faster than before. Best of all my knee doesn't hurt at all
after a run or even a weeks worth of runs. I have gone from running on average
15 miles a month at the beginning of the year - all which ended in pain - to
over 50 this month alone.</p>

<p>I have years to make up before I will be able to run at the speed that I ran
in high-school but thanks to Vibram Five Fingers I feel like it is possible
that I will be able to. As an added bonus in the last month I have lost 10
pounds as a result of running again. I still have about 20 pounds more to go
until I reach one of my goals of the year of getting down to 160 but thanks to
my new found love of running I am feeling lighter and healthier than I have
all year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
