<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: progress update | Zachary Zadell]]></title>
  <link href="http://zadell.com/categories/progress-update/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zadell.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-28T19:29:21-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://zadell.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zachary Zadell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update – 30 pounds down]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2010/progress-update-e28093-30-pounds-down/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-09T19:59:08-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2010/progress-update-e28093-30-pounds-down</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% img left http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5163/5247320766_bb6be9ff9e.jpg %}</p>

<p>I was actually confused this morning when I looked at my scale. I was
expecting to see 161 or 162 and hadn't expected to lose that last pound for
another few days. Coming back from my last trip where I was consistently
hovering just barely over 170 - loseit kept predicting my completion date as
getting ever closer to the end of the year. This made me think more and more
than it was unreasonable to lose 30 pounds in the time frame I wanted.</p>

<p>This past week I have had only one thing in mind with regards to my diet - eat
whatever I wanted to as long as I was under budget.
Loseit lists ice-cream as one of my favorite foods. This shows me that a large part of losing
weight is really about managing <em>how much</em> you eat.</p>

<p>For the first few months I ran and exercised like a mad man, which made me
feel great. Then when I was injured I didn't have the luxury of knowing that I
would be able to eat those 400-600 more calories thanks to my run. Loading up
on calories can be incredibly easy - a bag of chips, some ice-cream, eating
out. Bam - you just consumed more calories than your body can burn. So the
important thing for me was learning to manage my portions and how much I ate.</p>

<p>Now comes another challenge - not putting it all back on again.</p>

<p>My ankle is beginning to feel good enough to run on again and I am starting to
do more body weight exercises. I no doubt lost <em>some</em> muscle over the last
year and half where I didn't lift consistently so a part of me wants to try
and put that back on.</p>

<p>For now though I am thrilled to be going into the New Year knowing that I was
able to actually accomplish a weight loss goal.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update – 20 pounds down – 10 to go.]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2010/progress-update-e28093-20-pounds-down-e28093-10-to-go/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-19T17:26:33-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2010/progress-update-e28093-20-pounds-down-e28093-10-to-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% img left http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4091/5189532091_8eb17d3690_d.jpg %}</p>

<p>Those last 10 pounds took quite a bit longer than the first. Because of this I
almost feel like I have lost some perspective on how big a change it was for
me. My self image increased drastically going from 180-170. The first 10 were
rewarding but I couldn't really see the difference, with these last 10 it is
much more apparent.</p>

<p>I now have a BMI below 24.2, which means I am now at <em>normal weight</em>.</p>

<p>It was actually towards the end of October that I saw hints of being this low.
After major runs or tennis I would be in the low 170s. I figured with the way
I was going I would be in the 160s in no time. Then a couple of weeks ago (to
this day) I did something really dumb and ran on a strained ankle. Two weeks
later and that ankle is still hurting because of it. Then I went on a near
week long business trip that really tested my dieting resolve. Mid-way through
that I caught a cold - which I have spent the week fighting off. So the last
couple of weeks have put a major damper on my weight loss. I would guess the
last 3-4 pounds that I have lost have been exclusively because of dieting,
which is odd to me because I have relied so much on exercising for the first
16 pounds.</p>

<p>Today means I only have 8.8 pounds to go before I reach my goal of getting to
160. That number looks way smaller than 20 did a month and a half ago but it
looks huge when you consider that I will be attempting it by New Years -
especially during the holidays.</p>

<p>Part of my motivation for doing it before the New Year is so that I will be
able to go into the new year knowing that I am already at a good weight. So
instead of having to make yet another New Year's resolution of having to lose
weight I can make something else - like putting weight on (muscle), or even
just maintaining my weight.</p>

<p>Knowing how hard it was to lose these last 10 pounds makes me question if it
is even possible to lose another before the year ends with Thanksgiving and
Christmas coming up. We'll see how well that goes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update - 10 pounds down - 20 to go.]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2010/progress-update-10-pounds-down-20-to-go/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-27T06:12:11-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2010/progress-update-10-pounds-down-20-to-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zacharyz/5029052528/"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4113/5029052528_6497518cc8.jpg" alt="10 lbs down from 190" /></a></p>

<p>In just over 3 weeks I have made it 1/3rd a way through my goal of losing 30
pounds and weighing 160. I woke up this morning after refueling with my cheat
day to weigh 180.</p>

<p>It hasn't been easy - but it has been fun. During this past month I have
logged more miles running than ever before. According to Nike+ I have logged
about 20 miles in the past week alone and lowered my 5k time below 30 minutes.
Not bad for someone who only recently completed the Couch to 5k program about
10 days ago.</p>

<p>For the next 10 pounds I plan to incorporate more weight training with kettle
bells as well as some jiu jitsu training. This past month has been all cardio
and I fear that I might plateau if I don't mix it up.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
