<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: technology | Zachary Zadell]]></title>
  <link href="http://zadell.com/categories/technology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zadell.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-18T19:10:58-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://zadell.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zachary Zadell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Losing Weight with an iPhone - 5 Must Have Fitness Apps]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2010/losing-weight-with-an-iphone-5-must-have-fitness-apps/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-06T06:10:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2010/losing-weight-with-an-iphone-5-must-have-fitness-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4127/4963017072_df74617d5c_z.jpg" alt="iphone fitness
apps" /></p>

<p>Gone are the days of carrying a stopwatch and a notepad for workouts. These
days the number one tool is something many people carry with them - an iPhone.
For under $5 you can buy several apps that will make tracking your weight loss
a breeze. In this article I will cover the apps that I use on a daily basis to
track my progress and workouts.</p>

<h3>Lose It! (free)</h3>

<p>My favorite app by far is called Lose It! which just so happens to be free so
there is no excuse for not at least giving it a try. Lose It! is my tool of
choice for tracking my calories and my workouts.</p>

<p>Overview of how I use it:</p>

<ul>
<li>Track the calorie content of every meal that I eat.</li>
<li>Track every workout that I have.</li>
<li>Schedule 4 "motivator" alarms to remind me to eat on a regular basis.</li>
<li>Track my overall progress towards my weight goal.</li>
<li>Email me weekly reports</li>
<li>Share on facebook/twitter your exercises.</li>
<li>Share with my friends my weight loss progress and see theirs within the app.
That last feature is huge. Losing weight is way more interesting when you are
doing it with others. Watching daily/weekly progress of others is hugely
motivating.</li>
</ul>


<p>I used to keep a journal of all my workouts and exercises. Then I used to keep
a txt document and eventually a google doc of all my progress. Using a simple
<em>and free!</em> app to do it is so much easier.</p>

<h3>C25k ($2.99)</h3>

<p>In high-school I used to run cross country. It was just something I did in
between baseball and wrestling seasons to stay in shape. It was fun to meet
with friends after school and follow whatever workout the coach decided to
use. The best I ever got was around a 19 minute 5 kilometer race (6:30 mile
pace).</p>

<p>Those days are long gone.</p>

<p>Today I dread running and am lucky to run a 10 minute mile. This is something
that I want to change with the help of a very popular beginning running
program called Couch to 5k. It is a 9 week gradual program, where you are free
to go at your own pace. The over all goal is to be able to go from never
having run - to be able to run 5 kilometers without stopping.</p>

<p>There are a couple of popular apps on the iPhone that help you with this
program. I chose one called C25k based on its reviews but any of them will
probably do and will run you about $3. What it provides are audio cues for
when to warmup, run, walk and cool-down. It is basically a coach in your hand
that goes at your own pace. I recently finished my 7th week of the program and
am getting to the point where I feel comfortable running for 25 minutes - in a
few weeks I hope to be able to run for 45 minutes.</p>

<p>I will cover why I am focusing so much on running with my diet in a future
post.</p>

<h3>Nike+ (free + cost of sensor)</h3>

<p>Nike+ works in conjunction with a sensor that you put on your shoe that
measures the distance that you run. It has been around since before the iPhone
and I have been using it since the beginning because I am a stat tracking
junkie. I use it with C25k to measure my pace and track my runs.</p>

<p>The app itself is free and included with your iPhone or iPod Touch if you have
the sensor, which can be picked up in most running stores. It isn't the most
accurate device since it is heavily dependent on having a consistent stride
and can be a pain to properly calibrate. But it is still an excellent tool for
creating running workouts and tracking your progress.</p>

<p>The real meat is on the Nike+ website that saves all your runs (I have some
going back to 2007) that allows you to set personal goals (run 100 miles in a
year!) and see cute graphs of your runs.</p>

<p>Long after I have graduated from the C25k program I will still be using Nike+.</p>

<h3>100 pushups and 200 situps ($1.99 each)</h3>

<p>Another popular set of fitness programs are <a href="http://hundredpushups.com/">100
pushups</a> and <a href="http://www.twohundredsitups.com/">200 sit-ups
</a>.</p>

<p>Both workout programs are free to follow. I urge that you visit those sites to
get an idea of what is involved but I use these apps to help track my progress
and like the C25k program - get audio cues of when to workout or cool-down. I
am a huge fan of doing body weight exercises and both of those programs are
excellent. Last year I came very close to being able to do 100 pushups in a
row and 60 sit-ups in a minute with the aid of those apps.</p>

<p>Combine these programs with a pull-up workout and you will be in amazing shape
without the cost of a gym membership.</p>

<h3>iFitness ($1.99)</h3>

<p>iFitness is one of the top rated fitness related apps on the iPhone at 5 stars
and it is one of the best bargains too. I used to get annoyed with how often
the developer updated the app with new features. Today it is incredibly
polished and useful tool.</p>

<p>What it provides is a way to track workouts - how many sets, how much you
should be lifting each set, and what exercises you should be doing during the
workout. In the past I have used the <a href="http://stronglifts.com/">StrongLifts</a>
workout program to great success and it was easily tracked using iFitness.</p>

<p>It also provides a huge encyclopedia of exercises complete with videos
demonstrating proper form. It also has weight tracking and the ability to mail
yourself workout logs.</p>

<p>These are the 5 apps I use to motivate myself and track my weight loss
progress. Throughout the year I will be discussing extensively how I use them
to lose 30 lbs and get a level of fitness that I am proud of.</p>

<p>Do you use your iPhone to achieve your desired results? If so I would love to
hear how you do it.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Grado Labs Deserves Your Money]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2009/why-grado-labs-deserves-your-money/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-22T14:55:02-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2009/why-grado-labs-deserves-your-money</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in about 2003 I was really getting into listening to music. I was tired
of lame computer speakers and my gameboy headphones from 1989 were no longer
cutting it. To satisfy my desire to have clear, quality audio I got a pair of
<a href="http://gradolabs.com/product_pages/sr80.htm">Grado SR-80</a> headphones. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grado_Labs">Grado
Labs</a> isn't as famous to the average
music enthusiast as Sennheiser or Sony but around Hi-Fi audiophiles Grado has
made a name for themselves for providing a very crisp, neutral sound that is
true to the source material.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/7637913@N07/3746485759/"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3502/374648%0A5759_a7558de632_z.jpg" alt="kickin it with old school style" /></a>G
rado Labs is based out of Brooklyn and is a family owned business with the
sole purpose of manufacturing quality high-end audio products and it shows.
They make a wide range of headphones going from $49 iGrado street-style
headphones all the way up to crazy $1695 PS1000. The SR-80s were about $95
when I bought them. The main selling point for me was that they offered a
sound that was comparable to headphones that cost significantly more. If your
experience with headphones is limited to the cheap white ones that came with
your ipod then you are missing out on lot of detail in your music.</p>

<p>In about 2005 my headphones died due to a loose connection in one of the
drivers - probably because of over use. After a brief attempt at repairing
them myself which resulted in a mess of solder, I gave up not wanting to risk
doing more damage. In May of 2007 I was still bummed that these great
headphones were going to waste because of a tiny wire so I decided to send a
message to Grado to see if they could repair them. Despite the fact that the
headphones were a few years old they told me to send it in to the factory.</p>

<p>Holy Crap could a company really be that cool?</p>

<p>Thanks to my laziness I wouldn't find out for another 2 years. At the
beginning of July I decided to take a chance and mailed off the headphones
along with a letter explaining my situation. I figured my options were to
either trash these headphones which were going on nearly 3 years of not being
used or to send them off to Grado where the worst that could happen is that
they would be recycled.</p>

<p>Well today I got an unexpected delivery in the mail from Grado. In the box
were my repaired headphones free of charge and they sound as good as they ever
have.</p>

<p>Thank you so much Grado!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Nikon D90]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2008/the-nikon-d90/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-10T13:41:35-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2008/the-nikon-d90</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since getting a D40 back in March a lot has happened. I have really grown to
love photography and look forward to every trip and hike as an excuse to take
more pictures. I have gobbled up several books on the subject and have since
invested in a new lens and flash. I seldom go anywhere now without a camera.</p>

<p>I realized within a month of getting the D40 that I was going to out grow it
fast. It’s a great camera that takes amazing exposures and easily recommend it
over point and shoot cameras that cost more - but there are several
limitations that I won't cover here. Since I was happy with Nikon in general I
knew I would want to stay with their line of cameras. So my options were to
upgrade to the D80 or splurge on a D300. The D80 has long been at the end of
its product cycle - so while I could get it affordably I knew it wouldn't be
the upgrade that I really wanted. The D300 is considered one of the best
cameras to come out in the past year and is without a doubt my ideal upgrade.
But the cost was prohibitive. I enjoy photography but I am not willing to
spend upwards of $2k on a camera at this point.</p>

<p>Enter the D90.</p>

<p>The D90 has had an interesting journey. Those who follow DSLRs have known that
Nikon was certainly working on this camera. The D80 - while be very popular -
was looking long in the tooth compared to recent offerings by Canon. Most
notably the lack of LiveView and an old image sensor. This lead people to
theorize what would make a worthy successor. The dream was a D80 combined with
the award winning features of the D300. Nikon managed to deliver on that dream
and more.</p>

<p>The D90 inherits the D300 image sensor. Meaning it's megapixel count has been
bumped to 12 and it's sensitivity has increased dramatically over the D80
(from 3200 to 6400). It's LCD has been increased to 3 inches and has gained
Live View. In what many consider the biggest surprise the D90 is the first
DSLR to include video recording. Though this is probably the feature that I am
the least excited about.</p>

<p>A full feature comparison and "preview" can be found
<a href="http://www.dpreview.com/news/0808/08082702nikond90previewed.asp">here</a>. Chase
Jarvis did a fun post and video on the camera. You can find it
<a href="http://blog.chasejarvis.com/blog/2008/08/chase-jarvis-raw-advance-%0Atesting-nikon.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>I had planned on waiting until October or November for the body only release
of the D90 - but the combination of an upcoming vacation and a friend's
wedding had made me want to upgrade sooner. I had been saving up in
anticipation of the upgrade for a while so I was ready to purchase it whenever
it was available. On Monday I found out the local Best Buy had a one and
reserved it but I still wasn't certain as to whether I should make the
purchase as I am hesitant about making any big purchase. I shopped around at
the local camera stores and no one else had it in stock and luckily for me
Best Buy offered no interest financing for 2 years. That sealed the deal for
me - happy belated birthday to myself. I may very well be one of the first
people in Eugene with a D90.</p>

<p>So how is it?</p>

<p>Its everything I hoped for and more. It is a gigantic upgrade over my D40
while providing all the important features that I needed from the D300. There
are some things that I will probably miss (weather proofing, lens focus
tuning) but I can live without those for now. Shooting without a flash at
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/7637913@N07/sets/72157607086403265/">PAX</a> on a
D40 revealed a lot more noise than I would have liked. In comparison the D90
is able to take great looking pictures at 3200 where the D40 was barely able
to get by at 1600. Also I am able to use auto-focus on primes like my 50mm
1.8.</p>

<p>One of the major features I wanted from a D80 was the flash commander mode.
This allows you to use flashes off camera and control them from the camera. I
plan to get into <a href="http://strobist.blogspot.com/">Strobist</a> like photography in
the future.</p>

<p>I plan on selling the kit lens that came with it. While it is apparently a
good lens and well reviewed - I don't need it. I bought a Tamron 17-50 2.8
lens a few months back and have since not had a reason to use any of my other
lenses. So if anyone wants a 18-105 VR lens before it is sold in stores, I am
willing to part with it unused and with the warranty for $300.</p>

<p>Additionally my D40 is now for sale. I am willing to part with it and the
original kit lens for $300. That includes a spare battery. For $150 more I
will throw in my 55-200 VR kit lens. The D40 kit still sells for new at $460
at most stores - you can get it used with the 55-200 VR for less than that
from me. My <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/7637913@N07/">flickr account</a> is
filled with pictures that I took with this camera.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
