<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Apartment Living | Test Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://dakry.com/blog/categories/apartment-living/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dakry.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-21T15:57:59-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://dakry.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zachary Zadell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Apartment]]></title>
    <link href="http://dakry.com/blog/2007/08/19/new-apartment/"/>
    <updated>2007-08-19T10:58:27-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dakry.com/blog/2007/08/19/new-apartment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My buddies Sam and Brett helped me move into my new place yesterday.Â  It
was such a good feeling walking away from that old apartment, which was a such
a huge dump. I refused to do any cleaning to the place beyond picking up my
trash, so good luck trying to clean that place Bell.</p>

<p>Initially I had considered hiring some people to do the move for me. I found a
bidding service that lets you set the amount you want to pay, and then people
bid for the right to move your stuff. I figured it would be like ebay, where
you set your max bid and it doesn't go higher than that. Unfortunately bidding
started at my max, which was set unreasonably high, and the best bids were
never low enough. So we rented a uhaul instead, $50 later and our stuff was
moved.</p>

<p>The new place is amazing. Aside from having more room, it also has a better
layout, a deck, a garage (made unpacking so much easier), and a yard. Best of
all though is the location. The location of my last apartment was its best
feature. But this place does a good job of competing. Like the old place this
one has a Market of Choice near by, but this one is much bigger and feels a
lot nicer. Additionally there is a Wal-mart, Cafe Yum, and a ton of other
places to eat and drink at (no bars though). I think my favorite thing though,
which I only found out after I decided to live here, is that the swim and
tennis club is about 4 blocks from my door. That's closer than the University
was to my old place. What's incredible about all this is that the place is
very quiet compared to my old apartment despite being so close to so many
things.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bye Bye Bell]]></title>
    <link href="http://dakry.com/blog/2007/07/31/bye-bye-bell/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-31T01:53:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dakry.com/blog/2007/07/31/bye-bye-bell</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Little less than one month to go and I will be free of ever having to deal
with Bell Realty again.</p>

<p>I have admit over the last couple months I have been tempted to renew my
lease. My old room-mate left and got married to his childhood sweat-heart and
my neighbors from hell moved away - so I had the whole place to myself. On top
of that I got to have summer rates so the place has been dirt cheap and
probably more room than I needed.</p>

<p>Still I just couldn't bring myself to wanting to live here for another year.
The place really is a dump compared to what I could get elsewhere. It was a
serious spider and insect problem - the entrance looks like a dungeon. The
apartment washer and drier is always never available and is constantly a mess
from other tenants. The only thing it really has going for it is the location,
but I honestly don't think it is worth dealing with Bell any longer. Out of
the 10 units available in this apartment complex all but 3 are up for lease.
Likewise the apartment complex near by, also owned by Bell, has several units
available. Clearly people around Eugene have figured out that Bell is bad
news.</p>

<p>I put off looking for a new apartment until July as I figured any place I
found would not hold or wait until mid-August (when my lease ended) for me to
move in. So it wasn't until recently that Brett and I started looking for some
place. We first looked into this great little duplex neighborhood made up of
64 units. Rent was about a $130 more than what I payed currently but the
places were huge. Well worth the money, especially since they were month to
month. The only thing wrong with the place was that they were incredibly far
away from work and everything else.</p>

<p>The next place we looked at though was more promising. It was another duplex
near Applewood apartments and near Gold's Gym where I have been considering
getting a membership. Additionally it was close to a supermarket and a little
shopping area. It is also near a highway that leads right to work. So it was a
pretty good location over all. The duplex was about 30 more than what I
currently pay, had a deck, one car garage, a deck, a yard, a fireplace, a
washer and dryer hookup, and had more room over all with a nicer layout and
appliances. Unfortunately it was only one unit and Brett wasn't into sharing a
two bedroom with me (and my girlfriend). We are both in a stage in our lives
where living alone makes sense. Thankfully there was a unit right next store
that was almost identical that was also for rent but not from the same dude.</p>

<p>So that day I called the Realtor that was renting the place. It was a little
bit more a month than what Brett would be paying but the place was in a lot
better condition. Best of all it would be available the same time as Brett's
unit - mid August and was month to month. Perfect. So we found two places so
close to each other in a great location and for great prices. It was almost
serendipitous. But only if we both got them.</p>

<p>Brett applied for the duplex with me, in case I didn't get the place I would
just take the one he was originally interested in. We filled out applications
and drove to the realtor to dropped them off. We called ahead and were told
there was a drop box to place the applications and application fees. This was
on a Friday. On Monday we called to check if they got the applications only to
find out that they didn't. Apparently there was a cleaning crew over the
weekend who picked them up. At this point neither Brett nor I were happy. I
was potentially out of $100 in application fees and we were both out a lot of
personal information that we would rather not be without.</p>

<p>Thankfully a phone call later the Realtor was able to find out that neither of
the applications were lost and were in the hands of the owner. Unfortunately
for some odd reason they didn't take personal checks, so we had to go in
anyway with cash.</p>

<p>It turned out I was the only one applying for the place so the chances of me
getting it were pretty high. So Brett backed out and committed to the other
unit. The only thing really stopping me from getting this place was getting
references from Bell. Great.</p>

<p>When I turned in the application I told them it was probably going to be a
hassle since I was with Bell, the girl immidiately rolled her eyes and was
like "ahh yes we know all about Bell." It took them 6 faxes, an email from me,
and a week later before Bell finally confirmed my rental history.</p>

<p>So today I found out that I am approved for the place and I get to move into
it on the 15th. I am actually really excited about moving out of this
apartment and into a place that is so much nicer. Thankfully my last month of
rent is dirt cheap and pro-rated so I don't feel bad about giving Bell a final
month's rent.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[radiohead and neighbors]]></title>
    <link href="http://dakry.com/blog/2007/06/17/radiohead-and-neighbors/"/>
    <updated>2007-06-17T01:07:30-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dakry.com/blog/2007/06/17/radiohead-and-neighbors</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today marks the 10th anniversary of Radiohead's release of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OK_Computer">OK
Computer</a>.</p>

<p>OK Computer was one of the first and only CDs I have ever bought. I knew who
Radiohead was before that album but it wasn't until Paranoid Android did I
really take notice of "mainstream" music. Ten years later and Radiohead is
still one of my favorite bands and is up there with the Smashing Pumpkins who
recently got back together again.</p>

<p>I hope to see them both in concert some day!</p>

<p>On another note my neighbors from hell finally moved today. No I didn't say
good-bye. I did get to see their ragged couches out by the dumpster. For a
moment I contemplated claiming them then I remembered how disgusting those two
were.</p>

<p>My room-mate moved out at the beginning of the month and took all his clutter
so I suddenly found myself with more room than I know what to do with. The
first thing I did was clean up the place. I discovered several surfaces that
were white that I wasn't aware of. I also converted the living room to my main
bedroom. Its really nice waking up to a nice view of the river with natural
lighting. Its a shame Bell are such complete cock whores otherwise I would
gladly live here.</p>

<p>Apartment Living is good once again, at least for the next few months.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apartment Living pt 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://dakry.com/blog/2007/05/31/apartment-living-pt-4/"/>
    <updated>2007-05-31T13:29:59-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dakry.com/blog/2007/05/31/apartment-living-pt-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The good news is that my neighbors that I hate so much are moving out in June.
The bad news is that my lease is almost up and due to Bell Realty, the
apartment's new management, I am 99% certain I won't be renewing.</p>

<p>In April Bell sent out these letters asking if you wanted to renew the lease.
That's 4 months before the lease ended. If you didn't agree to renew they
immediately put your place up on their site advertising its available.</p>

<p>I called up Bell and explained why I wasn't willing to immediately renew
because the place had basically been lived in constantly since 2001 without
being cleaned once. So the only way I was going to renew the lease there was
if they replaced all the carpets and appliances and cleaned up the place. They
agreed to this with the only issue being that I move out for 2 weeks while
they did the cleaning. This wasn't a problem because I could just move my
stuff next store into my friend's place while they did the cleaning. Only
apparently they had leased out my friend's place while he was still in it.</p>

<p>That's right. 4 months left and they had already leased the place to someone
else. To make matters worse its the girls who live directly below him. When he
asked Bell "Wtf?" they responded that he couldn't apply for the same apartment
that he lived in. Swell.</p>

<p>At this point we weren't exactly thrilled. The main draw of living in such a
shitty apartment was that I was living next to a good friend and co-worker. If
he is getting the boot then the place isn't nearly as attractive. Additionally
I wouldn't be able to stay at his place while they cleaned.</p>

<p>So we wrote back Bell and tried to reason with them how it was ridiculous to
expect someone to commit 4 months in advance to renewing a lease. We even went
so far as to say that if my friend wasn't allowed to renew then I wouldn't be
renewing either. Two weeks past before we got a reply. Apparently the girl we
were in contact with decided to go on vacation and during that time the girls
who applied to the place had given their deposit. Her reply? Tough shit.</p>

<p>So it looks like I have two months to find a new place because at this point
there is no way I am willing to give these fucks anymore money.</p>

<p>Word to the wise: Stay clear of Bell Realty.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apartment Living pt 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://dakry.com/blog/2007/05/03/apartment-living-pt-3/"/>
    <updated>2007-05-03T13:55:35-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dakry.com/blog/2007/05/03/apartment-living-pt-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Getting hit with a big fat sound violation on a Saturday afternoon didn't sit
very well with Chris. A few days later we had talk. We had talked a couple
times before about the sound issues and each time Oliver managed to avoid it
and each time nothing good had come of it. The guy manages to disappear and
leave only Chris to deal with me and everyone else. I don't honestly know if I
would have <em>not </em>called the cops if I had known it was Chris who was making
all the noise because he is a good and reasonable guy in general. Up until
this point Oliver was the main source of annoyance and now he had pissed off
me and Chris - who was now faced with having to pay a fine he couldn't afford
and possible eviction if anything more happened in the future.</p>

<p>The gist of the conversation is that slow talking Chris expressed his anger at
the situation, I expressed my even greater anger, and Oliver tried to once
again avoid confrontation and leave everything on Chris. Everything about
Oliver rubs me the wrong way, from the way he dresses to the way he talks to
the kind of music he likes. It doesn't help that I have heard from his own
mouth what a horrible person he is so seeing him avoid a situation that he
created caused me to really lose my cool in a manner that I am not proud of. I
didn't hit him, but I was certainly on verge of doing it if he provoked me any
further.</p>

<p>He called me a "square" and flicked his cigarette at my feet.</p>

<p>I called him a "child" and a "clown."</p>

<p>Chris managed to raise his voice and show anger at Oliver for the first time.</p>

<p>The end result is that Chris agreed that Oliver was a problem and that he
would do his best to keep the noise levels down and avoid talking outside my
window as long as I agreed not to call the cops in the future.</p>

<p>If only that was the end.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
