<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: music | Test Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://dakry.com/blog/categories/music/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dakry.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-21T15:57:59-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://dakry.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zachary Zadell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Love Lies Dying]]></title>
    <link href="http://dakry.com/blog/2010/03/24/love-lies-dying/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-24T06:56:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dakry.com/blog/2010/03/24/love-lies-dying</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://za%0Adell.com/gallery/photo.php?id=4448855690"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4029/4448855690_818824477c.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>Coming from Eugene I am not used to local bands sounding good. They have the
instruments, and know how to play them but the end result usually isn't all
that great. It is funny because a lot of really good bands have come out of
Eugene, but at some point the music scene decided to move to Portland. So with
some trepidation I agreed to catch a live show from a friend's band, not
expecting much. If nothing else at least it would give me a chance hang out
with friends and try some music photography.</p>

<p>Thankfully the band - <a href="http://www.facebook.com/#!/pages/Love-%0ALies-Dying/130327486451">Love Lies Dying</a> - was actually quite good. The show took place at the
<a href="http://www.ashstreetsaloon.com/">Ash Street Saloon</a>.</p>

<p>I was tempted to just sit back the entire time and just enjoy the show, but I
noticed that no one else was really taking pictures. My D90 is a good camera,
but when it comes to the kind of low light photography that most music
photography demands - well there is a lot left to be desired. If I were going
to try and make an honest living out of this sort of thing I would definitely
want a full frame camera like a Nikon D700 or a Canon 5d mk II. Regardless I
am a strong believer in working with the tools that I have, so with that in
mind I threw on my fastest lens and decided to test a few shots - only to find
a blurry mess. I tried again with a flash and found the results were clear but
the flash had washed out the ambient stage lighting.</p>

<p>I was just about ready to give up when I got inspired by the work of a flickr
contact of mine named Todd who runs the site
<a href="http://ishootshows.com/">ishootshows</a>. I actually fired up the flickr app on
my iphone and started browsing his
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/toddowyoung/">stream</a> to pump myself up. I am
not going to pretend to be able to take as good of shots as Todd, but I wasn't
going to leave the show without giving it a second try.</p>

<p><a href="http://za%0Adell.com/gallery/photo.php?id=4448850022"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4035/4448850022_2444bc9509.jpg" alt="" /></a><a href="http://zadell.com/gallery/photo.php?id=4448071%0A445"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4%0A020/4448071445_e8d4cc2de7.jpg" alt="" /></a><a href="http:%0A//zadell.com/gallery/photo.php?id=4448846340"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4027/4448846340_cf37fed23b.jpg" alt="" /></a><a href="http://zadell.com/gallery/photo.php?id=444%0A8068169"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.c%0Aom/4009/4448068169_311c631af2.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>In the end I had a great time and the band appreciated me shooting the show.
The lessons I learned: take lots of shots, at least some are bound to be clear
and make heavy use of Lightroom's Luminance Noise Reduction.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Grado Labs Deserves Your Money]]></title>
    <link href="http://dakry.com/blog/2009/07/22/why-grado-labs-deserves-your-money/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-22T14:55:02-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dakry.com/blog/2009/07/22/why-grado-labs-deserves-your-money</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in about 2003 I was really getting into listening to music. I was tired
of lame computer speakers and my gameboy headphones from 1989 were no longer
cutting it. To satisfy my desire to have clear, quality audio I got a pair of
<a href="http://gradolabs.com/product_pages/sr80.htm">Grado SR-80</a> headphones. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grado_Labs">Grado
Labs</a> isn't as famous to the average
music enthusiast as Sennheiser or Sony but around Hi-Fi audiophiles Grado has
made a name for themselves for providing a very crisp, neutral sound that is
true to the source material.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/7637913@N07/3746485759/"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3502/374648%0A5759_a7558de632_z.jpg" alt="kickin it with old school style" /></a>G
rado Labs is based out of Brooklyn and is a family owned business with the
sole purpose of manufacturing quality high-end audio products and it shows.
They make a wide range of headphones going from $49 iGrado street-style
headphones all the way up to crazy $1695 PS1000. The SR-80s were about $95
when I bought them. The main selling point for me was that they offered a
sound that was comparable to headphones that cost significantly more. If your
experience with headphones is limited to the cheap white ones that came with
your ipod then you are missing out on lot of detail in your music.</p>

<p>In about 2005 my headphones died due to a loose connection in one of the
drivers - probably because of over use. After a brief attempt at repairing
them myself which resulted in a mess of solder, I gave up not wanting to risk
doing more damage. In May of 2007 I was still bummed that these great
headphones were going to waste because of a tiny wire so I decided to send a
message to Grado to see if they could repair them. Despite the fact that the
headphones were a few years old they told me to send it in to the factory.</p>

<p>Holy Crap could a company really be that cool?</p>

<p>Thanks to my laziness I wouldn't find out for another 2 years. At the
beginning of July I decided to take a chance and mailed off the headphones
along with a letter explaining my situation. I figured my options were to
either trash these headphones which were going on nearly 3 years of not being
used or to send them off to Grado where the worst that could happen is that
they would be recycled.</p>

<p>Well today I got an unexpected delivery in the mail from Grado. In the box
were my repaired headphones free of charge and they sound as good as they ever
have.</p>

<p>Thank you so much Grado!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[radiohead and neighbors]]></title>
    <link href="http://dakry.com/blog/2007/06/17/radiohead-and-neighbors/"/>
    <updated>2007-06-17T01:07:30-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dakry.com/blog/2007/06/17/radiohead-and-neighbors</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today marks the 10th anniversary of Radiohead's release of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OK_Computer">OK
Computer</a>.</p>

<p>OK Computer was one of the first and only CDs I have ever bought. I knew who
Radiohead was before that album but it wasn't until Paranoid Android did I
really take notice of "mainstream" music. Ten years later and Radiohead is
still one of my favorite bands and is up there with the Smashing Pumpkins who
recently got back together again.</p>

<p>I hope to see them both in concert some day!</p>

<p>On another note my neighbors from hell finally moved today. No I didn't say
good-bye. I did get to see their ragged couches out by the dumpster. For a
moment I contemplated claiming them then I remembered how disgusting those two
were.</p>

<p>My room-mate moved out at the beginning of the month and took all his clutter
so I suddenly found myself with more room than I know what to do with. The
first thing I did was clean up the place. I discovered several surfaces that
were white that I wasn't aware of. I also converted the living room to my main
bedroom. Its really nice waking up to a nice view of the river with natural
lighting. Its a shame Bell are such complete cock whores otherwise I would
gladly live here.</p>

<p>Apartment Living is good once again, at least for the next few months.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Decemberists Concert]]></title>
    <link href="http://dakry.com/blog/2007/05/05/the-decemberists-concert/"/>
    <updated>2007-05-05T01:46:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dakry.com/blog/2007/05/05/the-decemberists-concert</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got to see the Decemberists for the first time in concert on Thursday with
my girlfriend. I have been listening to them for just over a year now but
wasn't very enthusiastic about their new stuff aside from a few songs.
Thankfully they sound a million times better live than they do recorded, which
is remarkable considering how awesome they usually sound.</p>

<p>Colin Meloy has an amazing voice and stage presence for a nerd. I couldn't
help but thinking while watching him perform that even nerds can be rock
stars.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/210/483594993_e4c4cfb50b.jpg" alt="colin meloy rockin
out" /></p>

<p>They opened with Oceanside off their 5 songs album, which is one of my
favorite songs. Then they played their newer stuff with some chick from the
opening band singing the female part in Yankee Bayonet. She sounded a little
like Dido, which is a good thing, and put a softer edge to the song.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/215/483594959_8074211ad9.jpg" alt="yankee bayonet" /></p>

<p>One of the things that I have grown to like about Eugene is that a lot of
artists that I like so much have roots out of Eugene. Meloy used to go to the
local university and the bassist used to work at one of the local music places
called the WoW theater before joining the band.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/220/483561378_82211adbfe.jpg" alt="the band" /></p>

<p>That girl playing the huge keyboard covered the rest of the female lyrics.</p>

<p>One of the highlights of the show was when Colin Meloy took a camera from
someone in the front row of the audience and started taking pictures of
himself and everyone in the band.</p>

<p>The main highlight though was The Mariner's Revenge Song which didn't happen
until they came back on for the obligatory encore. That was the song that got
me hooked into the indi-folk style that The Decemberists do so well.</p>

<p>Aside from being the first show I saw at the Macdonald theater it also gave me
an opportunity to play with my new camera in such a dark setting. Its a <a href="http://www.dpreview.com/news/0602/06022111canons3is.asp">Canon
S3 IS</a> and
considering I was on the balcony at the very back of the theater I think it
did an admirable job.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
