<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: weekly summaries | Test Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://zadell.com/blog/categories/weekly-summaries/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zadell.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-22T00:31:19-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zadell.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zachary Zadell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Summary 11/29 - 12/5]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2010/12/06/weekly-summary-1129-125/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-06T21:15:11-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2010/12/06/weekly-summary-1129-125</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://30at30.zadell.com/wordpress/wp-%0Acontent/uploads/2010/12/weekly-summary-11-29.png"><img src="http://30at30.zadell.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/weekly-%0Asummary-11-29.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p><strong>3,175 calories</strong> under budget for the week. Lost <strong>1.8 pounds</strong> this week.<br/>
Still making progress - if not much. I feel like I am about 2 weeks tops from
reaching my goal for the year. I got as low as 162.3 this week, but for the
most part stayed around 163 throughout the week. With the end in sight I am
definitely appreciating just how much my body has changed in only ~27 pounds.
Even though I wasn't thrilled with how I looked at 190 I still felt that I was
better off than the majority of the population. People are really starting to
take notice though which feels awesome.</p>

<p>I am at the point where I can't imagine not using loseit to track my diet. I
don't want to go back to just eating whatever is put in front of me without
thinking about the consequences. That is what got me 30 pounds heavier in the
first place. I feel that with my current diet I am not getting enough food,
but because I am sidelined and not doing anything that requires mobility I
haven't needed to eat more than I am.</p>

<p>My ankle <em>still</em> feels jacked. I tried running on it earlier in the week and
didn't get more than a few blocks before I was back to hobbling. It is really
frustrating to get so into running only to be sidelined like this for as long
as I have been. Thankfully I am no longer suffering from that cold that I
suffered through for the past couple of weeks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Summary 11/22 – 11/28]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2010/11/30/weekly-summary-1122-e28093-1128/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-30T01:39:36-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2010/11/30/weekly-summary-1122-e28093-1128</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://30at30.zadell.com/wordpress/wp-%0Acontent/uploads/2010/11/weekly-summary-11-22.png"><img src="http://30at30.zadell.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/weekly-%0Asummary-11-22.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p><strong>1838</strong> calories under budget for the week. Lost <strong>2.8 pounds</strong> this week.<br/>
Another strong week and I did it even while indulging in a delicious
Thanksgiving Dinner. You will notice a small uptick on my weight loss graph
thanks to turkey.</p>

<p>I have been very strict when it comes to obeying my calorie budget and so far
the pounds have been flying off. I begin the new week at 164 lbs leaving just
4 more pounds to go before I reach my goal.</p>

<p>I have found that green tea has been my greatest weapon towards managing any
food cravings. Combine that with smaller food portions over all and it has
made weight loss seem easy.</p>

<p>At the beginning of the year I set a goal of getting down to 165 and it feels
good to complete yet another goal for the year. I am still determined to reach
my goal of losing 30 pounds over all though.</p>

<p>For the last couple of weeks I have been sick and am slowly recovering from my
ankle injury that has prevented me from exercising. I hope that this is the
final week that I will have to deal with either issue.</p>

<p>Just 4 pounds left - I can do this!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Summary 11/15 – 11/21]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2010/11/22/weekly-summary-1115-e28093-1121/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-22T21:14:36-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2010/11/22/weekly-summary-1115-e28093-1121</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://30at30.zadell.com/wordpress/wp-%0Acontent/uploads/2010/11/weekly-summary-11-15-10.png"><img src="http://30at30.zadell.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/weekly-%0Asummary-11-15-10.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p><strong>2743</strong> calories under budget for the week. Lost <strong>2.8 pounds</strong> this week.<br/>
What is this? An actual good week for weight loss? It feels like I was stuck
in the low 170s for a while and then this week I lost nearly 4 pounds (I
weighed in this morning at 166.8). All this despite not being able to run and
having a cold. It would be easy to point towards my cold as the source of my
weight loss, and that may turn out to be the case later, but it hasn't been
the sort of cold that has resulted in me puking a lot, so I don't think that
will be the case. Instead I look towards the strong calorie restriction that I
have been doing. Because I haven't been exercising I haven't needed to eat as
much I usually do, which means I have been consuming far less calories then
previously.</p>

<p>I also believe that I gave my body some time to recover from my trip, so once
it fully digested everything the weight started to fall off. I didn't even get
to see 169, as I went straight to 168.8 from the 170s, as I mentioned in an
earlier post.</p>

<p>If I can continue with this weight loss I am on schedule to complete my goal
mid-December. This doesn't factor in Thanksgiving of course. Still this means
it may actually be possible to make my goal before the New Year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Summary 11/8 – 11/14]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2010/11/17/weekly-summary-118-e28093-1114/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-17T03:20:58-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2010/11/17/weekly-summary-118-e28093-1114</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://30at30.zadell.com/wordpress/wp-%0Acontent/uploads/2010/11/loseit-report-11-8-10.png"><img src="http://30at30.zadell.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/loseit-%0Areport-11-8-10.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p><strong>389 calories</strong> over budget for the week. Lost <strong>0 pounds</strong> this week.<br/>
Injured and sick while on a company trip where they were paying for all the
food and drinks I could handle. How do you think things went? Despite several
days where I was over budget I was able to remarkable maintain my current
weight of 170.6.</p>

<p>I didn't want <em>not</em> enjoy myself so I picked and chose what calories I did
enjoy. White Mocha at Starbucks? Pass. Ginger Ale? Pass. Instead I saved
myself for delicious steaks and ramen and cut the easy snacks the rest of the
time.</p>

<p>So while I did enjoy myself I did try to stick to my calorie budget and the
results were that I was able to maintain my current weight. This makes me
happy but at the time it freaks me out because if it was that hard to simply
maintain my current weight then what is going to happen when I didn't have a
budget?</p>

<p>Not everyone can watch their diet, exercise or expect to be healthy every day.
If I wasn't actively tracking my calories I would have been clueless as to how
much I was actually eating and honestly it never felt like I was eating very
much.</p>

<p>The rest of this week I plan to be recovering from the cold I got last week
and resting my ankle. Hopefully next week I will be healthy enough to start
exercising again otherwise this week is going to be another week of
maintenance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Summary 11/1 – 11/7]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2010/11/17/weekly-summary-111-e28093-117/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-17T02:55:09-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2010/11/17/weekly-summary-111-e28093-117</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://30at30.zadell.com/wordpress/wp-%0Acontent/uploads/2010/11/loseitreport-11-8-10.png"><img src="http://30at30.zadell.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/loseitrepor%0At-11-8-10.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p><strong>3800</strong> calories under budget for the week. Lost <strong>1.4 pounds</strong> this week.<br/>
This week I continued where I left off and started upping my running distance
to 10ks. To mix it up some I tried to see how fast I could run a 5k.
Previously my fastest time was 29:06, I was able to destroy it with a time of
26:07. I decided to follow up this run with another 10k run on Friday that
didn't end so well. With about 2 miles left I felt my left ankle cramp some -
being a complete moron I decided to run through it for the rest of the run. I
can't stress just how bad an idea this was. If your body hurts - listen to it.
It turns out that it wasn't a cramp but a strain, and by running on it longer
for the next two miles I was just making it worse. For the rest of the week I
was unable to run - or even walk for that matter.</p>

<p>I also decided that I was going to quit my martial arts class. Studying jiu
jitsu and muay thai is actually something that I enjoyed quite a bit - but the
school itself not so much. At some point I got turned off because I kept being
grouped up with people who had even less experience than I had and by the
feeling that the people who were running the school were more interested in
getting me to test for belts rather than improving. This is unfortunate
because I was planning on relying on having the gym available to work out when
it gets too cold to run.</p>

<p>My main goal for this week was to get below 170 before a business trip in the
next week. My injury unfortunately got in the way of my progress and instead I
had to rely on strictly dieting - but I was able to get down to 170.6.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
