<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: lifestyle design | Zachary Zadell]]></title>
  <link href="http://zadell.com/categories/lifestyle-design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zadell.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-14T12:22:03-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zadell.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zachary Zadell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning to Run Again with Vibram Five Fingers]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2010/learning-to-run-again-with-vibram-five-fingers/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-27T02:56:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2010/learning-to-run-again-with-vibram-five-fingers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4079/4997164722_061f7d95a8_b.jpg" title="Vibram Fivefingers KSO Trek" ></p>

<p>When I was in high-school I used to run on the cross-country team. It was a
way for me to train in the off seasons between baseball and wrestling.
Eventually I actually became decent recording my fastest 5k time at around 19
minutes, which translates to about a 6 minute mile pace.</p>

<p>It was never easy and I never enjoyed it.</p>

<p>I remember starting every race without imagining what it would be like to
finish it. I simply put one foot in front of the other and kept pace with a
buddy until I could see the finish line - then I would sprint across it like a
mad man and puke my guts out.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3291/3015371980_6874e1ab49.jpg" title="Cross Country with Michael" ></p>

<p>I kept it up a little bit in college but over the years simply gave up on it. I think
around 5 years ago I was still able to run at an 8 minute mile pace.
Eventually though my knee began to hurt when I ran. Without a doubt my pains
are a result of years of playing tennis aggressively. There was a point when I
was playing almost daily that I couldn't imagine there being a ball that I
wouldn't try to track down and return. One day though something clicked and
since then there wasn't a hitting session or run that wouldn't end with my
knee swelling up and me being barely able to walk for a day.</p>

<p>I asked a doctor what could be done. He looked at my knee and determined that
there wasn't anything toren but there was a build up of cartilage that would
require surgery to remove. His advice: give up tennis - it simply wasn't worth
going through surgery when my knee was only aggravated when I played tennis.</p>

<p>As you could imagine this didn't sit well with me - after all tennis is
something that I love. It did force me to evaluate what exactly it was about
tennis that caused my knee to hurt. My conclusion was that it was caused by
the constant pounding, starting and stopping that occurs during tennis - all
of which is felt by my knee. Tennis shoes have an immense amount of padding on
the heel which only encourages you to drive your foot harder into the ground.</p>

<p>The more my knee hurt that more I hated myself for not running over the years.
I missed the days when I used to be able to fly across a field faster than the
wind. Now the very thought of it would cause my knee to ache.</p>

<p>My running stride in the past has always been very long. Where each stride I
would drive my heel into the ground and bound off of it like a deer. I used to
want to replicate the covers of running magazines that I saw when I was a kid.
Running shoes by their very nature encourage this type of stride despite how
un-natural it is. Try it for yourself - take off your shoes and go run across
a field. You will find that you will naturally land on the balls of your feet.</p>

<p>The human foot is the result of hundreds of thousands of years of evolution
and yet a couple of decades of marketing by shoe manufacturers have convinced
people that it is flawed and that they should be <em>corrected</em>. It was this line
of reasoning and the book Born to Run that lead me to buying the craziest
looking shoes that I had ever seen - Vibram Five Fingers.</p>

<p>I had put off buying a pair for well over a year. First because they aren't
exactly good looking, and second because I had a perfectly good pair of
running shoes. The selection of these expensive running shoes were the result
of going to a running store and having my stride recorded and analyzed so that
I would have the perfect running shoe for my feet. Compared to any other shoe
that I had ever had - running in these felt great. The only problem though is
that whenever I ran fast, I would go into my comfortable stride that involved
driving my heels into the ground which would lead to my knee hurting and me
regretting my decision to run.</p>

<p>The basic point of Vibram Five Finger shoes is to replicate what it is like to
be barefooted while still having the excellent traction and durability of a
Vibram sole. I went with the KSO (keep stuff out) trek model. Vibram makes a
model that is geared specifically towards road running, but I wanted something
that I could take on trails while still looking some what inconspicuous. The
average VFF has wild colors that I think most VFF enthusiasts appreciate
because they love the attention that they bring. I just wanted to be able to
run pain free.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4153/5029224752_a4d697649d.jpg"></p>

<p>It has been about 10 days since I got my pair of VFF. During that time I have
logged 21 miles and ran more consistently than I have ever before - or been
able to in the past. It feels awesome to wake up and actually want to be able
to run again instead of dreading the pain that would follow.</p>

<p>My stride has changed drastically. I have been trying for the past year to run
on the balls of my feet, but VFF make it so much easier. Instead of long
strides I now take short, quick steps that land below my center of gravity
rather than in front of it.</p>

<p>The result of this new way of running is that my stride is way more economical
than it used to be and my dropping 5k time is proof of it. I now feel like I
can run longer and faster than before. Best of all my knee doesn't hurt at all
after a run or even a weeks worth of runs. I have gone from running on average
15 miles a month at the beginning of the year - all which ended in pain - to
over 50 this month alone.</p>

<p>I have years to make up before I will be able to run at the speed that I ran
in high-school but thanks to Vibram Five Fingers I feel like it is possible
that I will be able to. As an added bonus in the last month I have lost 10
pounds as a result of running again. I still have about 20 pounds more to go
until I reach one of my goals of the year of getting down to 160 but thanks to
my new found love of running I am feeling lighter and healthier than I have
all year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changes and Upcoming Travels]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2010/changes-and-upcoming-travels/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-26T09:24:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2010/changes-and-upcoming-travels</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two of my goals for this year are to finally get a passport and to work abroad
for 2 months. I wasn't one of those fortunate kids who got to tour Europe out
of college or high school. After graduating I immediately began working and
aside from a trip back to Hawaii a few years ago I haven't had the opportunity
to leave the main land - let alone go to another country.</p>

<h2>New Job</h2>

<p>In May I was hired on by a very hot company called Unity Technologies as a web
developer. I had been contracting with them for about a month prior to being
hired. They also flew me down to San Francisco in April to be their official
photographer and to document their time at the Game Developers Conference.
Unity has long been a competitor in the middleware game engine space with a
company I used to work for - GarageGames. While GG shifted their focus over
the last few years to other <a href="http://instantaction.com">things</a>, Unity focused
on improving their core products and have steadily gotten better, and more
profitable over the years.</p>

<p>One of my requirements for working with them was that I have the freedom to
continue living in Portland, rather than move to San Francisco where their
North American office is based. We agreed that I would occasionally (about
once a month) work at the office, but the rest of the time I would be free to
work anywhere else. It has worked out for the most part except that their
<em>primary</em> office (and where the rest of the developers work) are actually in
Copenhagen, which is about a 9 hour time difference to Portland.</p>

<h2>Going to Copenhagen</h2>

<p>My project(s) are for the most part independent of what the rest of the
developers at Unity are working on. I focus primarily on web related projects
(store, site, etc), while the rest of the Unity is focusing on engine and tool
development. Still our paths do occasionally cross so it makes perfect sense
for me to become better acquainted with them. The solution then is to fly my
girlfriend and I over for at least a month, set us up in a hotel, and force us
to enjoy Copenhagen during the summer.</p>

<p>A co-worker has a vacation coming up at the end of July so they wanted to make
getting me out there a top priority so that we would have plenty of time to
work together. This gave me just the excuse I needed to get my passport, and
also gets me half way through another goal of working abroad for 2 months.</p>

<p>On July 6th I will be taking my first international flight to Copenhagen where
I will be working on-site for at least 3-4 weeks.</p>

<h2>Passport Acquired</h2>

<p>I had always entertained the idea of getting a passport whenever I went to the
post office. When I finally did go that purpose though the place was packed
with people had the same idea. Thankfully I was 2nd in the line, because it
took the guy almost an hour to process me alone. We got the fastest processing
time possible and my passport arrived in just under 2 weeks.</p>

<h2>Beyond Copenhagen</h2>

<p>I ended up getting us one way tickets to avoid having to commit to a departure
city and to keep our travels open ended. There is just way to much of Europe
that I would like to explore but I have neither the time or the money to do it
right now. We would like to see some of the near by countries like Germany,
Belgium, and the Netherlands. I also wouldn't mind being able to stay in a
single awesome city for a week and just explore the heck out of it. Either way
we have the month in Copenhagen to figure it out.</p>

<h2>Plans for this Site</h2>

<p>My plans are to be more active on this site in terms of documenting my
experiences with traveling - beyond my photography, though I promise there
will be plenty more of that. In preparation for my trip I finally graduated
from my flimsy $35 aluminum tripod that I got years ago to a nice, light,
travel-friendly carbon fiber Manfrotto tripod.</p>

<p>Expect lots of panoramas and HDR like shots in the future as we tour around
Copenhagen and beyond.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seven Goals for 2010]]></title>
    <link href="http://zadell.com/2009/goals-for-2010/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-25T16:15:06-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zadell.com/2009/goals-for-2010</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The past year has been a tremendous year for personal growth (of not only my
gut) and I see 2010 as the year where I execute on what I have learned. I
believe one of the best ways of holding yourself accountable for your goals is
to put them in writing. So here are mine:</p>

<h2>1) Move to Portland.</h2>

<p>I moved to Eugene in January of 2005 to work for GarageGames. Right about the
time of what will be my 5 year anniversary of having moved here I will be
moving to Portland where my girlfriend and I will be sharing a house with
another couple until we can find and afford a place of our own. I don't have a
job or any real prospects lined up and Portland has one of the highest rates
of unemployment in the nation, but compared to Eugene it has a heck of a lot
more going for it in just about every way that is important to us.</p>

<p>Coincidentally my girlfriend moved to Eugene during the same month as I did.
She completed her final term college this month and was able to finish her
Sociology degree. Remarkably, she was able to get a 4.0 (or better) in her
last 3 terms. By finishing up her degree we resolved the final reason for us
staying in Eugene. We both really adore Portland and so making the move there
is a huge step in the right direction for both of our futures.</p>

<h2>2) Continue to build out my Freelancing business</h2>

<p>One of my main reasons for moving to Portland is for the greater chance of
full-time employment, but at the same time I am not going to be waiting around
for companies to start hiring again.</p>

<p>The first half of the year really taught me what I value from myself and of my
professional life. It also taught me that I am pretty darn good at web
development and rekindled my love for it. My goal for the new year is to
continue getting freelance work and to <em>double my hourly rate</em>. I know
perfectly well that my current rate is actually well below what would be
considered standard for the quality of work that I do. But right now I am
concentrating on building up a portfolio of projects and work that I can use
to command the higher rate I deserve.</p>

<p>I registered an LLC in September and have since completed several projects
ranging from multiple Wordpress sites (including this one), Django powered
back-ends for iphone and heath care apps, and a Joomla site that required over
50 pages of content and a custom template and design. Every project has been
delivered on time and no doubt under budget.</p>

<p>All the projects that I have tackled so far have demonstrated expertise and
versatility in both front-and back-end web development, and my ability to
learn and adapt to changes quickly.</p>

<h2>3) Develop a passive income of at least $1000 a month</h2>

<p>The goal is to be able to generate enough income passively to be able to cover
my basic living expenses. The passive part is important. Passive income is
income that is generated by doing no additional work beyond the initial
investment. It happens regardless of whether you are sleeping or traveling.</p>

<p>The past year has shown me that I am capable of living fairly comfortably with
very little, all the while supporting my girlfriend through school and my mom
during this depression. Freelance work definitely has it highs and lows and
establishing a passive income enables me to take risks that I probably
wouldn't be able to do otherwise because I'll know that I have the freedom to
cover the necessities whether I am working or not.</p>

<p>I plan to do this with a combination of affiliate marketing sites as well as
ad revenue generated by some sides projects that I have in the works. This
goal will also help to facilitate goal #6.</p>

<h2>4) Lose 20 lbs.</h2>

<p>This goal is probably the closest I have to the typical new years resolution.
You would think that during a year where I have had the freedom to workout all
day/everyday I would be in tremendous shape. For the first half I actually was
because I basically worked-out and trained every day, but as I have focused
more on building my freelance career I have unfocused on other areas. I
haven't touched a tennis racquet or seriously gone to the gym since October.
Starting January that is going to change quite drastically and more
importantly I will be holding myself accountable.</p>

<p>For me, 20 lbs should be easy. At the moment I weigh around 185 lbs. My lowest
since college was in 2006 where I got down to 155 lbs. 165 will be a happy
medium for me where I won't be exceptionally lean but still be healthier
looking than I am presently.</p>

<p>I plan on achieving this weight loss the old fashion way - hard work and
dieting. I also plan to carefully document every workout that I do and every
food that I eat. By the end it should be clear to just about everyone what it
takes for me to lose weight.</p>

<h2>5) Develop at least 2 personal web projects.</h2>

<p>Blogs don't count. These are serious sites that are not done for clients and
that I will be doing both the design and development. They will serve my #3
goal. For the past year I have been developing a lot of quality ideas for
projects and 2010 will be all about executing on (some) of them.</p>

<p>While client work does help to sharpen my existing skills it doesn't really
help to push them in new directions. Working on these projects will help me
expand my expertise through working with new technologies.</p>

<h2>6) Finally get my passport, travel to a foreign country, and develop a</h2>

<p>proficiency in a second language</p>

<p>Some how I managed to not travel at all during the past year outside of
Oregon. Just about everyone else I know has used their time during this
depression to travel to Europe or some other continent. I was stuck here
focusing on sharpening my skills and helping my girlfriend get through her
final year of school. So one of my goals in 2010 is to finally get a passport
and to travel to another country. I am contemplating teaching English as a way
to get to either Japan or Korea.</p>

<p>Japan and Japanese is an obvious choice because I studied Japanese during
college and it is a place that I have always wanted to visit. To become
conversationally proficient would be possible in 6 months especially since I
am already familiar with the language and have numerous books and material on
it. Korean though would be a much greater challenge but since my girlfriend is
Korean I would have someone to personally converse with. Additionally my
girlfriend's parents live in Korea and she has been looking for a good time to
go back there to take advantage of their awesome healthcare. It would be
incredible to be able to go there and visit them.</p>

<p>Regardless of where I end up I plan to stay for at least 1-3 months and to
continue doing freelance work during that time.</p>

<h2>7) Sell my car</h2>

<p>My '94 honda civic has been through quite a lot since I got it. It has been
stolen and then nearly totaled, all while parked outside of my duplex in a
quite cul de sac. During that time it has treated me very well, but once I get
to portland I plan to relieve myself of the burden of having a car and stick
to public transportation and my bikes.</p>

<p>I also have a lot of other minor goals that I would like to achieve that
include stuff like becoming a better programmer, cooking more and eating
healthier, becoming a better tennis player and going on near weekly photo
trips to better my photography. Those are all general things that aren't very
measurable and living in Portland is certainly going to help with those.</p>

<p>The 7 goals I have mentioned are things that I want to passionately tackle
during the next year and reflect the direction that I want lead my life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
