<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: lifestyle design | Zachary Zadell]]></title>
  <link href="http://zaczadell.com/categories/lifestyle-design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zaczadell.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-22T22:46:32-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zaczadell.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zachary Zadell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning to Run Again with Vibram Five Fingers]]></title>
    <link href="http://zaczadell.com/2010/learning-to-run-again-with-vibram-five-fingers/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-27T02:56:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zaczadell.com/2010/learning-to-run-again-with-vibram-five-fingers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4079/4997164722_061f7d95a8_b.jpg" title="Vibram Fivefingers KSO Trek" ></p>

<p>When I was in high-school I used to run on the cross-country team. It was a
way for me to train in the off seasons between baseball and wrestling.
Eventually I actually became decent recording my fastest 5k time at around 19
minutes, which translates to about a 6 minute mile pace.</p>

<p>It was never easy and I never enjoyed it.</p>

<p>I remember starting every race without imagining what it would be like to
finish it. I simply put one foot in front of the other and kept pace with a
buddy until I could see the finish line - then I would sprint across it like a
mad man and puke my guts out.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3291/3015371980_6874e1ab49.jpg" title="Cross Country with Michael" ></p>

<p>I kept it up a little bit in college but over the years simply gave up on it. I think
around 5 years ago I was still able to run at an 8 minute mile pace.
Eventually though my knee began to hurt when I ran. Without a doubt my pains
are a result of years of playing tennis aggressively. There was a point when I
was playing almost daily that I couldn't imagine there being a ball that I
wouldn't try to track down and return. One day though something clicked and
since then there wasn't a hitting session or run that wouldn't end with my
knee swelling up and me being barely able to walk for a day.</p>

<p>I asked a doctor what could be done. He looked at my knee and determined that
there wasn't anything toren but there was a build up of cartilage that would
require surgery to remove. His advice: give up tennis - it simply wasn't worth
going through surgery when my knee was only aggravated when I played tennis.</p>

<p>As you could imagine this didn't sit well with me - after all tennis is
something that I love. It did force me to evaluate what exactly it was about
tennis that caused my knee to hurt. My conclusion was that it was caused by
the constant pounding, starting and stopping that occurs during tennis - all
of which is felt by my knee. Tennis shoes have an immense amount of padding on
the heel which only encourages you to drive your foot harder into the ground.</p>

<p>The more my knee hurt that more I hated myself for not running over the years.
I missed the days when I used to be able to fly across a field faster than the
wind. Now the very thought of it would cause my knee to ache.</p>

<p>My running stride in the past has always been very long. Where each stride I
would drive my heel into the ground and bound off of it like a deer. I used to
want to replicate the covers of running magazines that I saw when I was a kid.
Running shoes by their very nature encourage this type of stride despite how
un-natural it is. Try it for yourself - take off your shoes and go run across
a field. You will find that you will naturally land on the balls of your feet.</p>

<p>The human foot is the result of hundreds of thousands of years of evolution
and yet a couple of decades of marketing by shoe manufacturers have convinced
people that it is flawed and that they should be <em>corrected</em>. It was this line
of reasoning and the book Born to Run that lead me to buying the craziest
looking shoes that I had ever seen - Vibram Five Fingers.</p>

<p>I had put off buying a pair for well over a year. First because they aren't
exactly good looking, and second because I had a perfectly good pair of
running shoes. The selection of these expensive running shoes were the result
of going to a running store and having my stride recorded and analyzed so that
I would have the perfect running shoe for my feet. Compared to any other shoe
that I had ever had - running in these felt great. The only problem though is
that whenever I ran fast, I would go into my comfortable stride that involved
driving my heels into the ground which would lead to my knee hurting and me
regretting my decision to run.</p>

<p>The basic point of Vibram Five Finger shoes is to replicate what it is like to
be barefooted while still having the excellent traction and durability of a
Vibram sole. I went with the KSO (keep stuff out) trek model. Vibram makes a
model that is geared specifically towards road running, but I wanted something
that I could take on trails while still looking some what inconspicuous. The
average VFF has wild colors that I think most VFF enthusiasts appreciate
because they love the attention that they bring. I just wanted to be able to
run pain free.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4153/5029224752_a4d697649d.jpg"></p>

<p>It has been about 10 days since I got my pair of VFF. During that time I have
logged 21 miles and ran more consistently than I have ever before - or been
able to in the past. It feels awesome to wake up and actually want to be able
to run again instead of dreading the pain that would follow.</p>

<p>My stride has changed drastically. I have been trying for the past year to run
on the balls of my feet, but VFF make it so much easier. Instead of long
strides I now take short, quick steps that land below my center of gravity
rather than in front of it.</p>

<p>The result of this new way of running is that my stride is way more economical
than it used to be and my dropping 5k time is proof of it. I now feel like I
can run longer and faster than before. Best of all my knee doesn't hurt at all
after a run or even a weeks worth of runs. I have gone from running on average
15 miles a month at the beginning of the year - all which ended in pain - to
over 50 this month alone.</p>

<p>I have years to make up before I will be able to run at the speed that I ran
in high-school but thanks to Vibram Five Fingers I feel like it is possible
that I will be able to. As an added bonus in the last month I have lost 10
pounds as a result of running again. I still have about 20 pounds more to go
until I reach one of my goals of the year of getting down to 160 but thanks to
my new found love of running I am feeling lighter and healthier than I have
all year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
